[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Which are the three looping constructs provided by shell",
    "answer_a": "while",
    "answer_b": "for",
    "answer_c": "until",
    "answer_d": "foreach",
    "correct_answer":"while"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "What are the functions of Replication controller?",
    "answer_a": "It is responsible to control and administer the lifecycle of the pod.",
    "answer_b": "It helps the user to check the running status of the pod",
    "answer_c": "It is responsible to monitor and verify whether the allowed number of pod replicas were running",
    "answer_d": "It is responsible for routing the ingress traffic",
    "correct_answer": "It is responsible to control and administer the lifecycle of the pod."
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Which command can be used by the administrator to bring the system into single user mode?",
    "answer_a": "init s",
    "answer_b": "single",
    "answer_c": "init",
    "answer_d": "single s",
    "correct_answer": "init s"

  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "What is the Container Runtime?",
    "answer_a": "Software that is responsible for running containers",
    "answer_b": "An API object that manages a replicated application",
    "answer_c": "Stored instance of a Container that holds a set of software needed to run an application",
    "answer_d": "A command line tool for communicating with a Kubernetes API server",
    "correct_answer": "Software that is responsible for running containers"

  },

  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "What could be used to program additional authentication logic besides available authenticator modules?",
    "answer_a": "Kube Vault",
    "answer_b": "Authentication Proxy",
    "answer_c": "Kube Auth Service",
    "answer_d": "Kubernetes Role Manager",
    "correct_answer": "Authentication Proxy"
  },

  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Which HTML element defines the title of a document?",
    "answer_a": "<title>",
    "answer_b": "<head>",
    "answer_c": "<meta>",
    "answer_d": "<start>",
    "correct_answer": "<title>"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "A much better approach to establish the base URL is to use the ______ element.",
    "answer_a": "BODY",
    "answer_b": "HEAD",
    "answer_c": "BASE",
    "answer_d": "None Of The Above",
    "correct_answer": "BASE"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "________is an open-source project built to simplify and streamline using Docker on a Mac or Windows.",
    "answer_a": "Docker Cloud",
    "answer_b": "Docker Compose",
    "answer_c": "Docker Universal Control Plane",
    "answer_d": "Docker Kitematic",
    "correct_answer":  "Docker Kitematic"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Which operator is used to check if two values are equal and of same data type?",
    "answer_a": "==",
    "answer_b": "=",
    "answer_c": "===",
    "answer_d": "!=",
    "correct_answer": "==="
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "How to write an IF statement for executing some code if \"i\" is NOT equal to 5?",
    "answer_a": "if (i != 5)",
    "answer_b": "if (i <> 5)",
    "answer_c": "if i =! 5 then",
    "answer_d": "if i <> 5",
    "correct_answer": "if (i != 5)"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Which tag allows you to add a row in a table?",
    "answer_a": "<td> and </td>",
    "answer_b": "<tr> and </tr>",
    "answer_c": "<th> and </th>",
    "answer_d": "<cr> and </cr>",
    "correct_answer": "<tr> and </tr>"
  },

  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "How can you count for a particular pattern occurrences in a file?",
    "answer_a": "grep −c “pattern” <file>",
    "answer_b": "grep −k “pattern” <file>",
    "answer_c": "cat <file> | wc -k “pattern”",
    "answer_d": "cat <file> | wc -l “pattern”",
    "correct_answer": "grep −c “pattern” <file>"
  },

  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "The following command can be used for turning off or restarting a Linux host.",
    "answer_a": "reboot",
    "answer_b": "shutdown",
    "answer_c": "exit",
    "answer_d": "taskkill",
    "correct_answer": "shutdown"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Which command can be used to write onto other currently logged in user’s console output terminal.",
    "answer_a": "notify",
    "answer_b": "alert",
    "answer_c": "write",
    "answer_d": "broadcast",
    "correct_answer": "write"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "Which artisan command would you use to create a new Laravel Model?",
    "answer_a": "php artisan create:model ModelName",
    "answer_b": "php artisan model:make ModelName",
    "answer_c": "php artisan model create ModelName",
    "answer_d": "php artisan make:model ModelName",
    "correct_answer":"php artisan make:model ModelName"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "<TD> … </TD> tag is used for ________",
    "answer_a": "Table heading",
    "answer_b": "none of the above",
    "answer_c": "Table row",
    "answer_d": "Table Records",
    "correct_answer": "Table Records"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "This volume type can be used to share contents within containers in a pod, but will not persist beyond the life of a pod.",
    "answer_a": "EmptyDir",
    "answer_b": "Local",
    "answer_c": "ConfigMap",
    "answer_d": "FlexVolume",
    "correct_answer": "EmptyDir"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "The HTML global attribute, \"contenteditable\" is used to:",
    "answer_a": "Specify whether the content of an element should be editable or not",
    "answer_b": "Update content from the server",
    "answer_c": "Specifies a context menu for an element. The menu appears when a user right-clicks on the element",
    "answer_d": "Return the position of the first found occurrence of content inside a string",
    "correct_answer": "Specify whether the content of an element should be editable or not"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Which is the invalid file name in UNIX?",
    "answer_a": "LINUX",
    "answer_b": "a.widows",
    "answer_c": "bill .gates",
    "answer_d": "None of the above",
    "correct_answer": "None of the above"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Which command can give disk usage summary?",
    "answer_a": "chkdsk",
    "answer_b": "fdisk",
    "answer_c": "du",
    "answer_d": "df",
    "correct_answer": "du"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "Which is the log in which data changes received from a replication master server are written?",
    "answer_a": "Error Log",
    "answer_b": "Relay Log",
    "answer_c": "General Query Log",
    "answer_d": "Binary Log",
    "correct_answer": "Relay Log"
  },


  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Which оf the following class centers tabs/pills?",
    "answer_a": ".nav-justified",
    "answer_b": ".nav.navbar-nav",
    "answer_c": ".nav Nav-pills",
    "answer_d": ".nav-stacked",
    "correct_answer": ".nav-justified"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "If the Plesk server can't run Docker locally, you can still connect to a remote Docker server to manage containers. You'll need:",
    "answer_a": "A virtuozzo 6 container",
    "answer_b": "One separate ready-to-code environment",
    "answer_c": "A Windows Server",
    "answer_d": "The Plesk Docker extension",
    "correct_answer": "The Plesk Docker extension"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "The \"father\" Of MySQL Is ______.",
    "answer_a": "Bill Joy",
    "answer_b": "Stephanie Wall",
    "answer_c": "Bill Gates",
    "answer_d": "Michael Widenius",
    "correct_answer": "Michael Widenius"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "How can you create an E-mail link?",
    "answer_a": "<a Href=\"a@b\">",
    "answer_b": "<mail Href=\"a@b\">",
    "answer_c": "<a Href=\"mailto:a@b.com\">",
    "answer_d": "<mail>a@b</mail>",
    "correct_answer": "<a Href=\"mailto:a@b.com\">"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "What is the correct HTML element for playing video files?",
    "answer_a": "<movie>",
    "answer_b": "<media>",
    "answer_c": "<type=\"video\">",
    "answer_d": "<video>",
    "correct_answer": "<video>"
  },

  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "Choose the correct usage of ‘cd’ to move into the parent directory.",
    "answer_a": "cd",
    "answer_b": "cd ..",
    "answer_c": "cd..",
    "answer_d": "cd/",
    "correct_answer": "cd .."
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "Which of the following scripts will run successfully",
    "answer_a": "Users statistics SELECT customer name FROM customers;",
    "answer_b": "SELECT `customer name` FROM customers WHERE cat_id = 12 ORDER BY cat_id;",
    "answer_c": "SELECT FROM `customers` 'customer name';",
    "answer_d": "SELECT `customer name` FROM customers ORDER BY zone WHERE cat_id = 12;",
    "correct_answer": "SELECT `customer name` FROM customers WHERE cat_id = 12 ORDER BY cat_id;"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "How will you pass and access arguments to a script in Linux/Bash?",
    "answer_a": "scriptName “Arg1” “Arg2”….”Argn” and can be accessed inside the script as $1 , $2 .. $n.",
    "answer_b": "scriptName -arg “Arg1” “Arg2”….”Argn” and can be accessed inside the script as $1 , $2 .. $n.",
    "answer_c": "scriptName \"Arg1 Arg2….Argn” and can be accessed inside the script as $1 , $2 .. $n.",
    "answer_d": "scriptName “Arg1” “Arg2”….”Argn” and can be accessed inside the script as $Arg1 , $Arg2 .. $Argn.",
    "correct_answer": "How will you pass and access arguments to a script in Linux/Bash?"
  },


  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "The API server is also known as:",
    "answer_a": "kubeapi",
    "answer_b": "kube-server",
    "answer_c": "k8s-apiserver",
    "answer_d": "kube-apiserver",
    "correct_answer": "kube-apiserver"
  }
]
